<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSpy v2011 rel. 2 sp1 (x64) (http://www.altova.com) by Chris Koenig (Microsoft) -->
<MeritBadges>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>American Business</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ABIZ.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/American-Business.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Earning the American Business merit badge can help Scouts learn practical business matters that will be useful throughout life. Learning how businesses function will help you understand society and uncover a number of career options.</Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>American Cultures</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ACUL.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/American-Cultures.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The United States is a nation of immigrants. Every person came to America from somewhere else—or their ancestors did—and understanding these various cultural backgrounds can help Scouts to live in harmony with others in our varied and increasingly multicultural society. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>American Heritage</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/AHER.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/American-Heritage.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Every Scout swears to an oath that includes duty to his country. A better understanding of American heritage, the ways in which the past has lead to our present nation, is key to truly knowing what it means to be an American. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>American Labor</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/AMLB.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/American-Labor.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The labor movement in America seeks to ensure that the civil rights of laborers are protected in the workplace, especially in regard to wages, hours, and working conditions. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Animal Science</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ANML.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Animal-Science.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Cattle, horses, sheep, goats, hogs, poultry, and other domesticated animals are important to people for many reasons. They supply us with food and clothing, we use them for recreational purposes, they work with and for us. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Archaeology</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ARCA.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Archaeology.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Archaeologists are detectives who study how people lived in the past. They figure out what happened, when, how, and why. Using the clues that people left behind, they try to understand how and why human culture has changed through time. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Archery</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ARCH.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Archery.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Archery is a fun way for Scouts to exercise minds as well as bodies, developing a steady hand, a good eye, and a disciplined mind. This merit badge can provide a thorough introduction to those who are new to the bow and arrow—but even for the experienced archer, earning the badge can help to increase the understanding and appreciation of archery. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Architecture</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ARCI.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Architecture.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Architecture is not just the special buildings like cathedrals, museums, or sports stadiums we read about or see on television; it is as normal as the homes, places of worship, schools, and shopping malls where we live, worship, work, learn, and play every day. However, architecture is more than just common shelter; building has always satisfied the human need to create something of meaning. Even the simplest form of architecture is a work of art that requires thought and planning. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Art</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/AART.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Art.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>This merit badge concentrates on two-dimensional art, specifically drawing and painting in various media, including an introduction to design applications in the fields of graphic arts and industrial design, history and design principles, and how these fields relate to fine art. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Astronomy</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ASTR.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Astronomy.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>In learning about astronomy, Scouts study how activities in space affect our own planet and bear witness to the wonders of the night sky: the nebulae, or giant clouds of gas and dust where new stars are born; old stars dying and exploding; meteor showers and shooting stars; the moon, planets, and a dazzling array of stars. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Athletics</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ATHL.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://www.usscouts.org/usscouts/mb/worksheets/Athletics.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Being involved in an athletic endeavor is not only a way to have fun, but it also is one of the best ways for a person to maintain a healthy and strong body, living up to the promise each Scout makes "to keep myself physically strong." </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Auto Mechanics</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/AUTO.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Automotive-Maintenance.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Modern automobiles are important to many aspects of American life. Those who service automobiles must understand each principle, and how these principles interact to provide smooth, efficient performance. Owners of cars also benefit by understanding how their vehicles operate. This enables them to understand why certain periodic maintenance is required to keep their vehicles in tip-top shape. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Aviation</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/AVIA.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Aviation.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>For most of history, people have dreamed of flying, imagining how it would feel to soar through the sky like an eagle or hover in midair like a hummingbird, to float on unseen currents, free of Earth's constant tug, able to travel great distances and to rise above any obstacle. Today, through aviation, we can not only join the birds but also fly farther, faster, and higher than they ever could. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Backpacking</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/BACK.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Backpacking.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Earning the Backpacking merit badge will be demanding but rewarding. Scouts will learn what equipment to carry on their backs and what knowledge to have in their heads. In addition, Scouts will discover how to protect the environment by traveling and camping without leaving a trace. By mastering the basics of backpacking, Scouts will develop an even deeper respect for the outdoors. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Basketry</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/BASK.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Bird-Study.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Basketry is a handy skill for a Scout. A basket can be a sturdy companion on campouts, carrying clothes snugly and efficiently, holding potatoes and corn for roasting over a campfire, or carrying the day's fishing catch back to camp for dinner. Baskets and basket-weaving projects also make great gifts for family and friends. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Bird Study</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/BIRD.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Bird-Study.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Birds are among the most fascinating creatures on Earth. Many are beautifully colored. Others are accomplished singers. Many of the most important discoveries about birds and how they live have been made by amateur birders. In pursuing this hobby, a Scout might someday make a valuable contribution to our understanding of the natural world </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Bugling</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/BUGL.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Bugling.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Camping</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CAMP.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Camping.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Camping is one of the best-known methods of the Scouting movement. When he founded the Scouting movement in the early 1900s, Robert Baden-Powell encouraged every Scout to learn the art of living out-of-doors. He believed a young person able to take care of himself while camping would have the confidence to meet life's other challenges, too </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Canoeing</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CANO.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Canoeing.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>For several centuries, the canoe was a primary method of travel for explorers and settlers. Today, it remains an important part of the wilderness experience and an enjoyable leisure activity that teaches communication, teamwork, and physical fitness. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Chemistry</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CHEM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Chemistry.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Chemistry explores how substances react with each other, how they change, how certain forces connect molecules, and how molecules are made are all parts of chemistry. Stretch your imagination to envision molecules that cannot be seen—but can be proven to exist—and you become a chemist. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Cinematography</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CINE.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Cinematography.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Cinematography includes the fundamentals of producing motion pictures, including the use of effective light, accurate focus, careful composition (or arrangement), and appropriate camera movement to tell stories. In earning the badge, Scouts will also learn to develop a story and describe other pre- and postproduction processes necessary for making a quality motion picture. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Citizenship in the Community</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CITC.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Citizenship-in-the-Community.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>A nation is a patchwork of communities that differ from each other and may be governed differently. But regardless of how local communities differ, they all have one point in common: In the United States, local government means self-government. Good citizens help to make decisions about their community through their elected local officials. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Citizenship in the Nation</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CITN.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Citizenship-in-the-Nation.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>As Scouts fulfill the requirements for this merit badge, they will learn how to become active citizens are aware of and grateful for their liberties and rights, to participate in their governments and protect their freedom, helping to defend their country and standing up for individual rights on behalf of all its citizens. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Citizenship in the World</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CITW.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Citizenship-in-the-World.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Scouts who earn the Citizenship in the World merit badge will discover that they are already citizens of the world. How good a world citizen each person is depends on his willingness to understand and appreciate the values, traditions, and concerns of people in other countries. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Climbing</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CLIM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Climbing.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Climbing is not a sport that requires tremendous muscular strength; it demands mental toughness and the willingness to practice hard to master a set of skills. The adventure of climbing can also provide a new way to enjoy the outdoors. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Coin Collecting</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/COIN.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Coin-Collecting.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Coin collecting is one of the oldest of all hobbies. Hoards of ancient coins found in excavations indicate that coins were one of the first collectibles. From earliest times, people valued coins not only as a means of trading and storing wealth, but also as miniature works of art. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Collections</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/COLL.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Collections.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Collecting can be an educational and financially rewarding pastime: a collector must educate himself about a specific subject, be able to tell which items are worth preserving, how to catalog and organize his collection, and how to evaluate the value of items. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Communications</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/COMM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Communications.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>This clear and concise definition comes from the U.S. Department of Education: "Communication focuses on how people use messages to generate meanings within and across various contexts, cultures, channels, and media. The field of communication promotes the effective and ethical practice of human communication." </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Composite Materials</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CPMA.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Composite-Materials.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Composites can be found just about everywhere: in airplanes and sports cars, golf clubs and guitars, boats and baseball bats, bathtubs and circuit boards, and even bridges. Composites make bicycles and skis lighter, kayaks and canoes stronger, houses warmer, and helmets tougher. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Computers</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/COMP.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Computers.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Cooking</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/COOK.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Cooking.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The Cooking merit badge introduces principles of cooking that can be used both at home or in the outdoors. Scouts who earn this badge will learn about food safety, nutritional guidelines, meal planning, and methods of food preparation, and will review the variety of culinary (or cooking) careers available. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Crime Prevention</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CRIP.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Crime-Prevention.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Preventing crime, which can be as simple as reducing the opportuntities for crime to occur, is far less costly than apprehending and bringing legal action against those who break the law and it helps save people from the anguish of being victims. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Cycling</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/CYCL.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Cycling.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Since 1911, hundreds of thousands of Scouts have made the most of their two-wheel adventures by earning the Cycling merit badge. Whether you just got your first bicycle or have been cycling for years, you will learn more about your bike and what it can do by working on the requirements for this badge. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Dentistry</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/DENT.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Dentistry.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Teeth do a lot more than just peek out from under that winning smile. They have all sorts of duties, and having healthy teeth will help a person to eat, speak, and look great. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Disabilities Awareness</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/DISA.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Disabilities-Awareness.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Look around at the Scouts in your unit, the members of your sports teams, and the kids in your class - you will see that each person has their own personalities, distinct interests and ideas, different physical features, and different strengths and needs. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Dog Care</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/DOGC.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Dog-Care.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The love and interdependence between humans and dogs has endured for thousands of years. Evidence suggests that dogs and humans started relying on each other thousands of years ago. Today, dogs are our coworkers and companions. They assist search-and-rescue teams, law enforcement officers, hunters, farmers, and people with disabilities. They also play with us and keep us company. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Drafting</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/DRAF.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Drafting.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Drafting is a highly refined form of drawing used to communicate ideas to engineers, architects, and craftspeople. In earning this badge, Scouts learn the importance of accuracy and simplicity in developing a drawing that shows precise details in a simple format. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Electricity</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ELEC.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Electricity.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Electricity is a powerful and fascinating force of nature. As early as 600 BC, observers of the physical world suspected that electricity existed but did not have a name for it. In fact, real progress in unraveling the mystery of electricity has come only within the last 250 years. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Electronics</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ELET.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Electronics.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Electronics is the science that controls the behavior of electrons so that some type of useful function is performed. Today, electronics is a fast-changing and exciting field. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Emergency Preparedness</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/EMER.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Emergency-Preparedness.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Scouts are often called upon to help because they know first aid and they know about the discipline and planning needed to react to an emergency situation. Earning this merit badge helps a Scout to be prepared by learning the actions that can be helpful and needed before, during, and after an emergency. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Energy</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ENER.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Energy.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Saving, producing, and using energy wisely will be critical to America's future. If we are to leave future generations with a world in which they can live as well or better than we have, Scouts and other potential leaders of tomorrow must begin the hard work of understanding energy and the vital role it will play in the future. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Engineering</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ENGI.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Engineering.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Engineers use both science and technology to turn ideas into reality, devising all sorts of things, ranging from a tiny, low-cost battery for your cell phone to a gigantic dam across the mighty Yangtze River in China. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Entrepreneurship</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ENTR.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Entrepreneurship.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>By earning the Entrepreneurship merit badge, Scouts will learn about identifying opportunities, creating and evaluating business ideas, and exploring the feasibility (how doable it is) of an idea for a new business. They will also have the chance to fit everything together as they start and run their own business ventures. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Environmental Science</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ENVS.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Environmental-Science.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>While earning the Environmental Science merit badge, Scouts will get a taste of what it is like to be an environmental scientist, making observations and carrying out experiments to investigate the natural world. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Family Life</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/FAML.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Family-Life.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The family is the basic unit of society and is important to both individuals and communities. The world is rapidly changing, making today's society much more complex than ever before. As Scouts earn this merit badge, they will realize why it is important to know more about family life and how to strengthen their families. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Farm Mechanics</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/FARM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Farm-Mechanics.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>From the mattock and hoe to the horse and mule, the cotton gin and reaper, the tractor and air seeder—this is the story of farm equipment. Today, most farms are mechanized and farmers can do most of their own maintenance work and make the adjustments needed on their many intricate farm implements. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Fingerprinting</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/FING.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Fingerprinting.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>In earning the Fingerprinting merit badge, Scouts will learn about and use an important technique that is used by law enforcement officers, along with other materials like matching dental records and DNA sampling, to help identify amnesia victims, missing persons, abducted children, and others. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Fire Safety</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/FIRE.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Fire-Safety.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The ability to use fire safely is essential to human survival. By earning this merit badge, Scouts will learn to uses fire safely and responsibly, how to prevent home fires, and how to handle fire safely, as well as burn prevention, and camping safety. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>First Aid</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/FIRS.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/First-Aid.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>First aid — caring for injured or ill persons until they can receive professional medical care — is an important skill for every Scout. With some knowledge of first aid, a Scout can provide immediate care and help to someone who is hurt or who becomes ill. First aid can help prevent infection and serious loss of blood. It could even save a limb or a life. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Fish and Wildlife Management</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/FAWM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Fish-and-Wildlife-Management.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Wildlife management is the science and art of managing the wildlife—both animals and fish—with which we share our planet. Maintaining the proper balance and the dynamics that go with it requires humankind's attention. We use this stewardship tool to help minimize or eradicate the possibility of extinction of any given species. We want our descendants to have the opportunity to experience the same animal diversity that we now enjoy. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Fishing</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/FISH.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Fishing.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Every Scout ought to be able to fish in order to get food for himself. A tenderfoot [beginner] who starved on the bank of a river full of fish would look very silly, yet it might happen to one who had never learned to catch fish. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Fly Fishing</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/FLYF.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Fly-Fishing.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Fly-fishing is a specialized form of fishing that combines skill and artistry. Because it is so rich with tradition, it is a passion for millions of people. The beauty of the water, the solitude, and the skills that the sport requires have made fly-fishing very important in the lives of many notable people. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Forestry</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/FORE.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Forestry.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>In working through the Forestry merit badge requirements, Scouts will explore the remarkable complexity of a forest and identify many species of trees and plants and the roles they play in a forest's life cycle.They will also discover some of the resources forests provide to humans and come to understand that people have a very large part to play in sustaining the health of forests. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Gardening</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/GARD.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Gardening.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Humans have been growing plants for thousands of years. Farmers and horticulturists make their living growing food and other plants, while other people grow gardens for pleasure. Becoming a good gardener requires a Scout to understand the science of growing plants—how to prepare the soil, how to select and plant seeds, and how to care for the growing plants. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Genealogy</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/GENA.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Genealogy.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Exploring your roots—where your family name came from, why your family lives where it does, what your parents and grandparents did for fun when they were your age—can be fascinating. Discovering your ancestors back through history is what genealogy is all about. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Geocaching</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/GEOC.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Geocaching.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Geology</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/GEOL.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Geology.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Geology is the study of Earth. It includes the study of materials that make up Earth, the processes that change it, and the history of how things happened, including human civilization, which depends on natural materials for existence. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Golf</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/GOLF.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Golf.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Golf is unique because the players police themselves. Other sports depend upon referees or umpires to apply penalties when there are infractions of the rules. In golf, every player is expected to act honorably, and the welfare and integrity of the game rely on every player's honesty. This is why golf often is referred to as a "gentleman's game." </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Graphic Arts</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/GRAP.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Graphic-Arts.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The field of graphic arts includes many kinds of work in the printing and publishing industries. Graphic arts professionals are involved in the creation of all kinds of printed communication, from business cards to books to billboards. The scope of printing communications is huge. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Hiking</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/HIKE.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Hiking.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Hiking is a terrific way to keep your body and mind in top shape, both now and for a lifetime. Walking packs power into your legs and makes your heart and lungs healthy and strong. Exploring the outdoors challenges you with discoveries and new ideas. Your senses will improve as you use your eyes and ears to gather information along the way. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Home Repairs</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/HOME.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Home-Repairs.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Successfully completing this badge's requirements can lead to a lifetime of personal and financial rewards: Doing basic home repairs provides a sense of personal pride in one's achievements and increased self-confidence. In addition, safe and successful do-it-yourselfers can easily save a family thousands of dollars in repair bills over the years. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Horsemanship</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/HRSM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Horsemanship.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>In addition to learning how to safely ride and care for horses, Scouts who earn this merit badge will gain an understanding of the instincts and behaviors of horses and humane and effective methods for training horses. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Indian Lore</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ILOR.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Indian-Lore.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Far different from the stereotypes or common images that are portrayed on film, on television, and in many books and stories, American Indians have many different cultures, languages, religions, styles of dress, and ways of life. To learn about these different groups is to take an exciting journey of discovery in which you will meet some of America's most fascinating peoples. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Insect Study</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ISTU.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Insect-Study.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>In earning the Insect Study merit badge, Scouts will glance into the strange and fascinating world of the insect. There, they will meet tiny creatures with tremendous strength and speed, see insects that undergo startling changes in habits and form as they grow, and learn how insects see, hear, taste, smell, and feel the world around them. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Inventing</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/INVE.jpb</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Inventing.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Inventing involves finding technological solutions to real-world problems. Inventors understand the importance of inventing to society because they creatively think of ways to improve the lives of others. Explore the world of inventing through this new merit badge, and discover your inner inventiveness. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Journalism</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/JOUR.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Journalism.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>One thing is for sure about journalism: It is never boring. For a reporter, almost every day is different from the last. One day you might interview the mayor of the city, the next day report on a car accident, and the day after that preview a new movie. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Landscape Architecture</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/LAND.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Landscape-Architecture.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Landscape architects design and plan the various outdoor spaces in modern communities - neighborhood parks, soccer fields, school grounds, places of worship, office parks, shopping malls, cemeteries, and lakes - creating outdoor places that people will care about and want to visit. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Law</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/LLAW.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Law.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Earning this merit badge enables a Scout to learn about the history and kinds of laws, the purpose and methods of law enforcement, consumer protection agencies, emerging law, and careers in the legal profession. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Leatherwork</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/LEAT.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Leatherwork.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Scouts who complete the requirements to earn the Leatherwork merit badge will explore leather's history and its endless uses. They will learn to make a useful leather item using the same types of raw materials that our ancestors used; be challenged to master skills like hand-stitching, lacing, and braiding.; and learn how to preserve and protect leather items so they will last a lifetime and beyond. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Lifesaving</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/LIFE.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Lifesaving.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>No Boy Scout will ignore a plea for help. However, the desire to help is of little use unless one knows how to give the proper aid. The main purpose of the Lifesaving merit badge is to prepare Scouts to assist those involved in water accidents, teaching them the basic knowledge of rescue techniques, the skills to perform them, and the judgment to know when and how to act so that they can be prepared for emergencies. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Mammal Study</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/MAMS.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Mammal-Study.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>A mammal may weigh as little as 1/12 ounce, as do some shrews, or as much as 150 tons, like the blue whale. It may spring, waddle, swim, or even fly. But if it has milk for its young, has hair of some kind, is relatively intelligent, and has warm blood, then it is a mammal. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Medicine</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/MEDI.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Medicine.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The practice of medicine has a rich history that spans several centuries. Since the first use of plants and other items as simple medicines and balms, many men and women have contributed to the advancement of the "healing arts." </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Metalwork</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/META.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Metalwork.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Scouts will begin their work on this merit badge by learning about the properties of metal, how to use simple metalworking tools, and the basic metalworking techniques. Then they will practice using these tools and techniques before concentrating on the more intricate skills of one of four metalworking options. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Model Design and Building</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/MDAB.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Model-Design-and-Building.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Model making, the art of creating copies of objects that are either smaller or larger than the objects they represent, is not only an enjoyable and educational hobby: it is widely used in the professional world for such things as creating special effects for movies, developing plans for buildings, and designing automobiles and airplanes. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Motorboating</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/MOTO.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Motorboating.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>With the fun of operating a motor boat boat comes the responsibility for keeping that boat in first-class condition, knowing and obeying the nautical "rules of the road," and gaining the general knowledge and skills to operate a boat safely. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Music</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/MUSC.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Music.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The history of music is rich and exciting. Through the ages, new music has been created by people who learned from tradition, then explored and innovated. All the great music has not yet been written. Today, the possibilities for creating new music are limitless. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Nature</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/NATU.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Nature.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>There is a very close connection between the soil, the plants, and all animal life, including people. Understanding this connection, and the impact we have upon it, is important to preserving the wilderness, as well as to our own well-being as members of the web of nature. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Nuclear Science</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/NUKE.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Nuclear-Science.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Nuclear science gives us a simple explanation of the natural world. The ultimate goal of nuclear science is to find out if there is one fundamental rule that explains how matter and forces interact. Earning the Nuclear Science merit badge is a chance for Scouts to learn about this exciting field at the cutting edge of science today. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Oceanography</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/OCEN.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Oceanography.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The oceans cover more than 70 percent of our planet and are the dominant feature of Earth. Wherever you live, the oceans influence the weather, the soil, the air, and the geography of your community. To study the oceans is to study Earth itself. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Orienteering</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ORIE.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Orienteering.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Orienteering, the use of map and compass to find locations and plan a journey, has been a vital skill for humans for thousands of years. Orienteering is also a recognized sport at the Olympic Games, and thousands of people participate in the sport each year in local clubs and competitions. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Painting</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PANT.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Painting.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>This merit badge provides an opportunity for Scouts to learn more about painting, including both the artistic and practical aspects. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Personal Fitness</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PERF.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Personal-Fitness.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Personal fitness is an individual effort and desire to be the best one can be. Regardless of their current levels of personal fitness, in the twelve weeks it will take Scouts to complete the athletic requirements for this merit badge, they will be in better shape, feel better about themselves, have more energy, and gain self-confidence in their overall abilities. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Personal Management</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PERM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Personal-Management.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Personal management is about mapping a plan for your life that will involve setting short-range and long-range goals and investigating different ways to reach those goals. Education, training, and experience all help make your goals become a reality. To achieve your goals, you will choose the best path and make a commitment to it, while remaining flexible enough to deal with changes and new opportunities. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Pets</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PETS.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Pets.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Pet ownership is a mixture of fun, excitement, responsibility, commitment, expense, and learning. Besides providing a window into the animal world, owning pets gives us opportunities to participate in activities that strengthen the human-animal bond. Pet ownership teaches us about the responsibility we have to the other living beings on this planet, and pets can be just plain fun. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Photography</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PHOT.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Photography.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Beyond capturing family memories, photography offers a chance to be creative. Many photographers use photography to express their creativity, using lighting, composition, depth, color, and content to make their photographs into more than snapshots. Good photographs tell us about a person, a news event, a product, a place, a scientific breakthrough, an endangered animal, or a time in history. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Pioneering</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PION.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Pioneering.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Plant Science</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PLSC.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Plant-Science.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Plant scientists use their curiosity and knowledge to develop questions about the world of plants. Then they try to answer those questions with further observations and experiments in the laboratory and in the field. To earn this merit badge, Scouts will explore three of the most important plant science specialties: agronomy, horticulture, and field botany. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Plumbing</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PLUM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Plumbing.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Plumbing, including pipe fitting, is an important and well-paid occupation. The industry is quite broad. It covers installations and repairs in homes, commercial properties, and factories. Plumbing pipelines are used for water supply, waste drainage, natural-gas heating, and many other purposes. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Pottery</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/POTT.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Pottery.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The Pottery merit badge provides an introduction to pottery making, enabling Scouts to gain skill and understanding from actually creating pottery. Completing the requirements will include hands-on production of a work of art, from start to finish. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Public Health</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PUBH.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Public-Health.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The field of public health deals with maintaining and monitoring the health of communities, and with the detection, cure, and prevention of health risks and diseases. Although public health is generally seen as a community-oriented service, it actually starts with the individual. From a single individual to the family unit to the smallest isolated rural town to the worldwide global community, one person can influence the health of many. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Public Speaking</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PUBS.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Public-Speaking.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>A lot happens during the course of every person's life and your ability to communicate your feelings and ideas is the best way to connect to the larger world. Even if you haven't stood at a podium on the stage and find the whole idea scary, sooner or later, someone is going to ask you to get up and say a few words. If you are prepared, it won't be scary. It can even be fun. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Pulp and Paper</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/PULP.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Pulp-and-Paper.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Here's an astonishing number to digest. Each person in the United States uses about 700 pounds of paper each year. Paper is everywhere in our lives. Every year in the United States, more than 2 billion individual books, 24 billion newspapers, and 350 million magazines are published on paper. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Radio</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/RADO.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Radio.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Radio is a way to send information, or communications, from one place to another. Broadcasting includes both one-way radio (a person hears the information but can't reply) as well as two-way radio (where the same person can both receive and send messages). </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Railroading</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/RAIL.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Railroading.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>By earning this badge, Scouts can learn about the history of railroading, its place in modern society, careers in railroading, and hobbies related to railroading. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Reading</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/READ.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Reading.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>If you have ever wanted to go back in time or wished you could visit the future, if you are curious about the world, or if you are interested in how things work or like to learn new things, these are all reasons why you should want to read. Reading is fascinating. It's full of surprises. And it will take you places you can't get to in any other way. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Reptile and Amphibian Study</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/RAAS.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Reptile-and-Amphibian-Study.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Boys always have been interested in snakes, turtles, lizards, and alligators, as well as frogs and salamanders. Developing knowledge about these captivating creatures leads to an appreciation for all native wildlife; understanding the life cycle of a reptile or amphibian and keeping one as a pet can be a good introduction to natural history; and knowing about venomous species can help Scouts to be prepared to help in case of an emergency. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Rifle Shooting</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/RIFL.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Rifle-Shooting.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Unless a rifle is handled incorrectly or recklessly, it is not dangerous. A rifle, like any other precision instrument, is manufactured to perform a specific task and can do so at no risk to the user or others. By earning this badge, Scouts can develop their shooting skills while learning safe practices. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Robotics</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ROBO.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Robotics.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Rowing</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/ROWG.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Rowing.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Rowing is the use of oars as a means of propelling boats, has grown from a basic method of transportation to a competitive sport and an enjoyable method of exercising. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Safety</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SAFE.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Safety.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Knowing about safety helps Scouts to make the right choices and to take the best actions to avoid accidents by making informed choices in their everyday activities and to respond appropriately during an emergency situation. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Salesmanship</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SALE.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Salesmanship.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>By studying salesmanship, Scouts can learn self-confidence, motivation, friendliness, and the persistence necessary to overcome obstacles and solve problems. Sales can offer a challenging and rewarding career for those who enjoy interacting with people from all walks of life. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Scholarship</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SCHO.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Scholarship.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Working on the Scholarship merit badge provides Scouts with a great opportunity to become more successful in school. They will learn how to improve their skills in the classroom, develop good study habits, and master techniques for writing reports and taking tests. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Scouting Heritage</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SHERI.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Scouting-Heritage.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Scuba Diving</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SCUBA.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://meritbadge.org/wiki/images/a/af/Scuba_Diving.pdf</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Sculpture</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SCUL.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Sculpture.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>This merit badge introduces Scouts to sculpture, an art form that allows an artist to express what he sees and feels by using these three dimensions by shaping materials such as clay, stone, metal, and wood. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Shotgun Shooting</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SSHO.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Shotgun-Shooting.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>A shotgun is a precision instrument, designed to shoot a shot charge in a specific pattern to cover a designated area at a certain distance. Unlike a rifle, the bore of the shotgun is not rifled, so the shot emerging from the muzzle is not spinning. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Skating</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SKAT.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Skating.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>This merit badge introduces Scouts to the exciting world of ice skating, roller skating, and in-line skating. In addition to being an enjoyable leisure activity that promotes fitness, there are a variety of athletic careers in skating. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Small-Boat Sailing</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SMBS.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Small-Boat-Sailing.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Sailing is one of the most enjoyable pastimes on the open water. The quiet and peacefulness of the water can provide a pleasant break from everyday life. However, smooth sailing requires paying careful attention to safety. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Snow Sports</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SNOW.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Snow-Sports.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Skiing and snowboarding are the fastest and most thrilling ways to travel on foot in snow country. These sports also provide the physical benefits of fresh air, rhythmic action, and strenuous exercise. Many games and contests give snow sports variety and added rewards. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Soil and Water Conservation</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SOIL.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Soil-and-Water-Conservation.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Conservation isn't just the responsibility of soil and plant scientists, hydrologists, wildlife managers, landowners, and the forest or mine owner alone. It is the duty of every person to learn more about the natural resources on which our lives depend so that we can help make sure that these resources are used intelligently and cared for properly. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Space Exploration</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SPEX.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Space-Exploration.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Space is mysterious. We explore space for many reasons, not least because we don't know what is out there, it is vast, and humans are full of curiosity. Each time we send explorers into space, we learn something we didn't know before. We discover a little more of what is there. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Sports</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SPOR.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Sports.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>Millions of people participate in sports every year. For some the appeal is the close friendships that come with being part of a team. Some revel in the joy of victory and lessons of defeat. For some, the personal fitness is so important that exercise becomes a daily need. And still others desire the feeling of achievement, that feeling of measurable improvement that comes with dedication to a sport. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Stamp Collecting</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/STAM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Stamp-Collecting.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description>The world's most popular hobby, stamp collecting is enjoyed by millions throughout the world. Through this hobby. you can experience history: postage stamps are like tiny windows that introduce the people of the world to the country's leaders, customs, history, products, and environment. </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Surveying</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SURV.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Surveying.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Swimming</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/SWIM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>True</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Swimming.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Textile</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/TEXT.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Textile.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Theater</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/THEA.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Theatre.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Traffic Safety</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/TRFS.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Traffic-Safety.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Truck Transportation</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/TRTR.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Truck-Transportation.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Veterinary Medicine</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/VETM.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Veterinary-Medicine.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Water Sports</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/WATR.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Water-Sports.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Weather</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/WEAT.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Weather.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Whitewater</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/WITE.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Whitewater.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Wilderness Survival</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/WILD.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Wilderness-Survival.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Wood Carving</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/WOODC.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Wood-Carving.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
	<MeritBadge>
		<Title>Woodwork</Title>
		<ImageUrl>/Images/MeritBadges/WOOD.jpg</ImageUrl>
		<IsEagleRequired>False</IsEagleRequired>
		<WorksheetUrl>http://usscouts.org/mb/worksheets/Woodwork.doc</WorksheetUrl>
		<Description> </Description>
	</MeritBadge>
</MeritBadges>
